A comedy about growing up… and the bumps along the way.
Juno is a comedy, drama, romance film directed by Jason Reitman.
Faced with an unplanned pregnancy, sixteen year old high-schooler, Juno
MacGuff, makes an unusual decision regarding her unborn child.
Juno MacGuff, played by Elliot Page.
Paulie Bleeker, played by Michael Cera.
Vanessa Loring, played by Jennifer Garner.
Mark Loring, played by Jason Bateman.
Mac MacGuff, played by J.K. Simmons.
Bren MacGuff, played by Allison Janney.
Juno is a 2007 American coming-of-age comedy-drama film
directed by Jason Reitman and written by Diablo Cody.
Elliot Page stars as the title character, an independent-minded teenager confronting her
unplanned pregnancy and the subsequent events that put pressures of adult life onto her.
Michael Cera, Jennifer Garner, Jason Bateman, Allison Janney and J.
Simmons also star.
Filming took place in 2007 in Vancouver, British Columbia.
It premiered on September 8 at the 2007 Toronto International
Film Festival, receiving a standing ovation.
Juno won the Academy Award for Best Original Screenplay and earned three other nominations for Best Picture, Best Director for Reitman, and
Best Actress for 20-year old Page (who was presenting as female at the time, and is the sixth-youngest nominee in the category).
The film's soundtrack, featuring several songs performed by Kimya Dawson in various guises, was the first
chart-topping soundtrack since 2006's Dreamgirls and Fox Searchlight's first number-one soundtrack.
Juno earned back its initial budget of $6.5 million in twenty days, the first
nineteen of which were when the film was in limited release.
It went on to earn $232.3 million worldwide.
Juno received acclaim from critics, many of whom placed the
film on their top-ten lists for the year.
It has received criticism and praise from members of both the anti-abortion and
abortion rights communities regarding its treatment of abortion.
The film explores themes of puberty, first time,
becoming an adult, sexuality, pregnancy.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting and emotional.